OLEKSII FOKIN

DATA ANALYST

last projects: ANALYSING CONVERSION RATES

ANALYSING PRODUCT METRICS FOR SOFTWARE SERVICE COMPANY

CONTACTS

- +380992918798
- ✓ oleksiifokin@gmail.com
- Vinnytsia, Ukraine

HARD SKILLS

- SQL
- Python
- Processes optimisation and automation
- Web design
- Video editing

TOOLS

- Tableau
- Power BI
 (In the process of learning)
- Photoshop
- Illustrator

LANGUAGES

- English: Intermediate
- Ukrainian: native
- Russian: native

EDUCATION

2024

GO-IT GLOBAL

Data Analyst

1998 - 2004

IGOR SIKORSKY KYIV POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE"

Department of automation of electromechanical systems and electric drives

• Engineer electromichenic

PROFILE SUMMARY

I have always been fascinated by the "magic" of numbers, formulas, and graphs, and in 2024, I had the opportunity to turn this passion into a profession by becoming a Data Analyst.

My experience in engineering, analysing leaks and mistakes in Texas Hold'em Poker (using Hold'em Manager soft), web design, video editing, as well as agriculture and optimising workflows in a military headquarters (since 24.02.2022) has taught me to work with large volumes of information, identify patterns, and make data-driven decisions.

I believe this unique skill set will help me become a productive team member and bring real value to the field of data analytics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Private Company "GERAX"

2003 - 2008

Engineer

- Collected, analyzed, and interpreted data on technical processes at sites (reservoir park, oil pumping station)
- Developed technical specifications and documentation for process automation.
- Designed process automation diagrams to optimize equipment operations.
- Created data visualizations and technical drawings to support decision-making.
- Developed user manuals and instructions to facilitate the use of technical systems

Cereus Poker Network

2008-2012

Online Poker player. Multitabling

- Every day after a session, analysing own game and the game of your opponents.
- Finding optimal solutions and leaks analysis to identify recurring actions that lead to significant losses and decrease ROI.
- Offline analyse 50,000 to 100,000 played hands per month.
- Over 50 metrics for analysis.
- 50+ unique opponents per month.
- Developed analytical thinking and risk management strategies by evaluating large datasets in real-time.
- Result: 5 Big Blinds per 100 hands (\$2.54/100 hands)

Military Service in the National Guard

/Military Unit A3027

2014 - 2015

Commander of the Assault Unit. Lieutenant

Military Service in the Armed Forces

27/02/22 - now

/Military Unit A****

Company Commander. Captain

- Personnel control
- Control of military property and equipment inventory
- Maintaining the moral and psychological state of servicemen
- Ensuring timely supply of the servicemen
- Monitoring the technical condition of equipment and weapons
- Maintaining the combat readiness